

michele clemmens GRAPHIC DESIGNER

ABOUT



micheleclemmens@gmail.com



856-316-8201



www.micheleclemmens.com

I have 9 years of experience in large format printing, sign & graphics production, & team management. I have an expert knowledge of the Adobe Creative Suite, file preparation, & photo editing. I am able to discuss a job with a client and manage a project fully from estimation, to design, to production while overseeing multiple employees. I am comfortable with ordering from outside vendors, loading machinery, helping with installations, as well as all social media and web design needs.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Five Below | Visual Merchandise Coordinator | 2019- Present

- Creates all Preliminary and Final merchandising layouts using AutoCAD, as well as any supplemental signage needed within our department.
- Works with store design, allocations, and buyers to ensure that each unique new store opens with the proper seasonal set and that all visual standards are executed.
- Designs set tags & multi-page set guides using product images and CADS to directly train the store crews in the field how to properly set all product according to Visual Merchandising standards.

Image360 Marlton | Art Director | 2014-2019

- Designed Vehicle Wraps, business cards & print collateral, tradeshow displays, architectural signage, dimensional lettering, window & wall graphics, event promotion signage, and much more.
- Loaded and ran all machinery, including an HP 360 Large Format Printer, Vinyl Plotter, Trotec Laser Cutter and ADA Engraving Machine.
- Helped with production & installation of signage, including plotting, weeding, cutting and laminating.
- Maintained all social media accounts, edited all product photos, designed marketing materials, rebuilt and updated website.
- Vectorized or recreated most customer files, and set up properly for print or contour cut
- Obtained pricing for substrates or outsourced projects, created invoices, placed orders with outside vendors.
- Managed the workflow of all employees and projects while being responsible for interviewing and training newly hired employees.

InkIT Design & Print | Graphic Designer | 2013-2014

- Designed Vehicle Wraps, Business Cards, Logos, Promotional Products, Banners, as well as set up files for in house and outsourced printing.
- Brainstormed with customers directly to solve their signage needs and then worked closely with the production department to ensure files were ready to rip and print.



michele clemmens GRAPHIC DESIGNER

Advertising Systems, Inc | Graphic Designer | 2012-2013

- Designed Vehicle Wraps, Flyers, E-Blasts, Website Graphics, Tradeshow Displays, Album Artwork, etc.
- Set up files for UV and solvent printing, die cutting, laser engraving.
- Worked with the sales department to create marketing materials for events.
- Edited and photoshopped professional photos for magazines and catalogs.
- Managed and met production deadlines to ensure events ran smoothly and all graphics were installed on time.

Showcase Graphics | Designer & Office Manager | 2010-2012

- Created all social media accounts and marketing materials, and maintained website.
- Photographed all completed products, edited photos for use in marketing.
- Set up design files and placed orders with outside vendors.
- Designed graphics for promotional products, apparel, and print collateral.
- Handled invoicing, payments, and all internal paperwork while managing work flow inside the office.

30 Strikes | Bartender/Cook/Waitress | 2003-Present

- Input customer orders and process cash & credit card payments.
- Prep, cook, and deliver all food & beverage orders for 80 lanes.
- Created custom cocktails & designed the menus for bar & cafe.
- Attended bartending school & TIPS Certification to learn and maintain proper food and beverage safety.
- Organize food service for large tournaments and all spectators during events such as the Special Olympics and Intercollegiate Championships.

SKILLS

Adobe Creative Suite

AutoCAD

Wix, Wordpress, Keynote

Microsoft Office

Corebridge Order Mgmt

Flexi Sign Design

Onyx RIP Center

Summa Sign Pro Vinyl Plotter

HP360 Large Format Printer

Trotec Laser Software

PROFESSIONAL EXPERTISE

Photo Retouching & Manipulation

Vectorization & Logo Design

Pre-Press file setup

Production & Offsite installation

Back-end website editing

Newsletter & E-blast design Social Media Marketing

Invoicing & Reconciliation

Corporate Re-Branding

Site Inspections and Client Meetings

EDUCATION

Rowan University 2011

Bachelor of Arts in Graphic Design Minor in Art History

Burlington County College 2009

Associate of Applied Science in Graphic Design & Digital Media